Professional Experience

2011 - PRESENT

White Lion Interactive

LEAD DESIGNER

I create a range of visuals from mobile to desktop and various platforms in between. I am involved in all aspects of the creative process from client interviews and content strategy to building design systems and developing creative ideas. I build wire frames, style guides, design concepts, static prototypes and develop finished code for the web.

2001 - PRESENT

Chawlie

INDEPENDENT DESIGNER

I've worked with small business and independent individuals who want a custom creative design to help them stand out. Working as an independent designer has allowed me to stay on top of current trends and pushed me to further my creative spirit and quest for knowledge.

2003 - 2011

i2i Group

INTERACTIVE DESIGNER

As the Interactive Designer I designed and developed small business websites, created print advertising for various publications, designed numerous direct mail pieces, laid out merchandise catalogs, color corrected fine jewelry and precious metals, lead press checks, and provided creative direction on every project.

Profile

Ambitious and confident self starter who loves web design and all the complexities that come along with building things on the internet. Passionate about Typography, Web Design and Development. Recent tasks include creating wire frames, content strategy, developing design systems for the web, thinking through user experience and creating development code. Creating structure, grids and organization is imperative to great design. Clearing the clutter helps users stay focused.

- Creative Direction
- User Experience
- Content Strategy
- Wireframing User Workflows
- Concept Presentations
- Brand Development
- Design Strategy and Style Guides for Developers
- Mobile Design
- Web Development

Education

Bachelor of Fine Arts in Communication Design from Texas State University 2001

Skills

- Adobe Creative Suite: Photoshop, InDesign, Illustrator
- HTML, CSS, SASS, Github, Wordpress, Sublime Text, Foundation Zurb, UXPin
- Mobile and Responsive Web Design
- General Understanding: PHP, Javascript, Laravel and MVC development methods